

# GET IN TOUCH WITH ME

Mobile: 8130516737 Email: himansh.dit@gmail.com Address: Bangalore, India

#### **SKILLS**

#### **DEVOPS TOOLS**

- GIT- Version Control System
- Docker-Containerization Tool
- Jenkins
- JIRA
- SVN
- Apache
- Tomcat
- Maven
- GITHUB

# IT INFRASTRUCTURE

- Microsoft Azure
- Oracle
- Active Directory
- SSO
- LINUX

## **PROGRAMMING**

- Python
- SQL
- OOPS

# HIMANSHU SAHU

# Python Developer and DevOps Engineer

## **SUMMARY**

Follow the philosophy of "Less is more". Currently working as a Member of Technical Staff- Dev at MetricStream. I Have over 3+ years of IT experience. I'm passionate about the Development with operations domain along with automation.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

5 Star Rated Employee for the year 2019-2020 May 2020 MetricStream

LIMS Certified Aug 2018 Pfizer

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Project History at MetricStream (MTS-Dev)

Barclays (Europe) | Jul 2020 - Mar 2021

- Deployed and managed E-GRC application on multiple platforms like Microsoft Azure (Customer Location), Docker, Virtual Machines in both Windows and Linux environments.
- Expertise in GIT, Jenkins, Apache and Dockers to automate the build and deploy of E-GRC application in various customer environments.
- Collaborated in Development of Log Analyzer tool using python which gives the additional functionality while debugging in case of any issues.
- Planning & designing Database Architecture as per client's requirements and executing tasks such as the creation of tablespaces, user maintenance, database security imposition and backup.

#### Shell (India) | Nov 2018 - Mar 2021

- Collaborated with customer and internal teams during project life cycle to resolve multiple issues related to Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment (CI/CD),Database, E-GRC instance, App Server, Web Server, Browsers, SSO, Git Source Code Management, Docker and Jenkins.
- Installing value adds (LDAP, SSO and so on), and 3rd party products such as BCL and MQs and boosted various activities with respect to the following:
  - Infrastructure Validation, capacity Planning, installation of GRC Application, Patch Deployments.
  - Customer Training and Customer specific documentation leading to smooth user experience.
- Performed end to end troubleshooting, managed scalability, performance and skilled in expediting troubleshooting actions to business-critical enterprise-wide application Issues

## Project History at Infosys (Software Engineer)

 Managed and maintained LIMS tool and build a web application "Text Summarization" using python and K-Means Clustering Algorithm.

## **EDUCATION**

# Jaypee Institute of Information Technology

Bachelors of Computer Science Engineering (CGPA 7.1)